# Marguerite Mei

(647) 997-5519 | mgrtmei@gmail.com | Toronto, ON

## **Core Competency**

Master of Management, Accounting & Finance, 4 years' analytical experience in Financial Analysis, Corp Accounting, CRM and Marketing. Strong technical thinking, hands on implementation in various data reconciliation, transformation and data visualization projects. A true problem solver and team player!

### Qualification

## ✓ Financial Analyses

Finance & Accounting, Reconciliation & Auditing, Budget & Forecasting, SAP Order-to-Cash Cycle;

## ✓ CRM & Marketing

Banking Customer Migration & Segmentation; Market Share; Campaign Analysis; LVMH

#### ✓ Data Analyses

Data Integration, Data Quality & Cleansing; Data Gap Analysis; DB queries & Semantic layer

#### ✓ Data Visualization

Power BI, Tableau, Google Analytics, KPI design, Report Automation, Business Requirement Collection

#### **Tech Skills**

- Data: Advanced SQL, Power BI, Tableau, Google Analytics, MS Access, Enterprise Excel, VBA, Python
- Application & Tools: SAP Sales & Distribution, SPSS, draw.io, Jira, Confluence, ServiceNow, Windows Task Scheduler
- Platform: SQL Server, Snowflake, Azure Cloud, Databricks, Data warehouse

#### **Education**

Master of Management, Accounting and Finance	University of Windsor	Sep 2020 - Jun 2022
Bachelor of Commerce with Honors	York University, ON	Sep 2014 - Oct 2019
Diploma certificate, Professional Accounting	Seneca College, ON	Sep 2019 - Aug 2020
Certificate: Google Analytics Basic & Advanced, Digital Campaign	Google	Aug 2022

## **Work Experience**

# Data Analyst

# **EDPYPF Services Inc.**

Jun 2022 - Current

- Banking transaction analysis via RFM model on customer migration and segmentation for launching new credit card
- Designed Power BI dashboard on expense control with YoY and actual vs. budget analysis
- Collected business requirement through business meeting, data investigation to identify business logic & KPI formula etc
- Monthly Income Statement Reporting Automation using VBA in Access and Excel, which saved 80% time on repeated work
- Answered various ad hoc business questions and analyzed industry trends in Customer Sales database and action on closing gaps with resolving data duplicate and data integrity issues

## **Financial Analyst**

## **Ginis Electronics Technology LLC**

Sep 2017 - Dec 2021

- Worked with bank, internal / external stakeholders on accounting related, like financing, insurance, securities, credit cards, finance income statement and balance sheet.
- Accounts bookkeeping maintenance and data reconciliation for GL, AP, AR in SQL Server 2014
- Worked with 3rd party company on monthly, quarterly and yearly adjustment, posting, auditing and financial reporting
- Automated invoicing process through Excel Marco, VBA to upload invoice data to accounting table in database.
- Managed 10+ marketing channels across multiple industries seeking for business opportunities in short turnover periods; Arranged project set-up and execution liaising with certain regional demand analyses
- Analyzed and grasped client core demands quickly; Well-prepared with explicit business workflow, objectives, and deliveries

# **Business Analyst**

#### **Axis Communications Inc.**

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

- Collaborated with stakeholders from sales and service teams to collect business requirements and lead initiative solutions in data manipulation process; Prepared SQL queries for routine and ad hoc analysis
- Planned event for distributors training campaign, creating contents, tracking, analyzing subscribers
- Developed potential customer through questionnaire and interviews & identified core group through scoring based selection
- Made strategy presentation; praised by C-level clients for research-based insights, establishing new business opportunities

# **Projects Experience**

•	Bell strategies to accelerate prepaid gross subscriber additions	University of Windsor	May 2022
•	Customer based Brand Equity Management Project	University of Windsor	Dec 2021
•	Marty's Department Store – Customer Grouping & Campaign Analyses	York University	Sep 2020